// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
      numb: 1,
      question: "What is a queue in data structure?",
      answer: "A linear data structure",
      options: [
        "What is a queue in data structure?",
        "A linear data structure",
        "A non-linear data structure",
        "An abstract data type"
      ]
    },
  
  
      {
      numb: 2,
      question: "Which operation in a queue adds an element to the rear of the queue?",
      answer: "Enqueue",
      options: [
        "Dequeue",
        "Enqueue",
        "Peek",
        "Rearrange"
      ]
    },
    
   
    {
      numb: 3,
      question: " In a queue, which item is considered the first to be removed (First-In, First-Out)?",
      answer: "Rear element",
      options: [
        "Front element",
        "Rear element",
        "Middle element",
        "Random element"
      ]
    },
     
  
      {
      numb: 4,
      question: "What is the time complexity for the enqueue operation in a queue with n elements?",
      answer: "O(1)",
      options: [
        "O(n)",
        "O(log n)",
        "O(1)",
        "O(n^2)"
      ]
    },
   
    {
      numb: 5,
      question: "What is the term for a situation where a queue is empty and you attempt to dequeue an element?",
      answer: "Queue underflow",
      options: [
        "Queue overflow",
        "Queue underflow",
        "Queue imbalance",
        "Queue depletion"
      ]
    },
     
  
    {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What is the main disadvantage of using an array to implement a queue?",
    answer: "Limited size",
    options: [
      "Inefficient insertion and deletion operations",
      "Limited size",
      "Difficulty in accessing elements",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
   
  
  
  {
  numb: 7,
  question: "Which operation can be used to check if a queue is empty?",
  answer: "IsEmpty",
  options: [
    "IsFull",
    "NotEmpty",
    "IsEmpty",
    "IsQueue"
  ]
  },
     
  
  {
  numb: 8,
  question: "Which data structure is used for implementing a breadth-first search algorithm?",
  answer: "Queue",
  options: [
    "Queue",
    "Linked List",
    "Stack",
    "Binary Tree"
  ]
  },
  
     
  
  {
  numb: 9,
  question: "What is the primary use of a queue in computing?",
  answer: "Managing tasks and job scheduling",
  options: [
    "Implementing recursion",
    "Sorting data",
    "Managing tasks and job scheduling",
    " Storing data in random order"
  ]
  },
     
  
  {
  numb: 10,
  question: " Which queue operation removes all elements from the queue?",
  answer: "Clear",
  options: [
    "Enqueue",
    "Dequeue",
    "Peek",
    "Clear"
  ]
  }
      
  ];